<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Datascience on Dusty Turner</title>
    <link>/categories/datascience/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Datascience on Dusty Turner</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© This post is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License，please give source if you likes to quote or reproduce.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/datascience/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2018 Goal: Read 1000 (Children&#39;s) Books</title>
      <link>/post/analysis-of-my-children-s-reading-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/analysis-of-my-children-s-reading-list/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionOver Christmas 2017, my wife Jill resolved that our family (to include babysitters) would read our children over 1000 new books in 2018. More specifically, 29 December 2017 - 28 December 2018.
A goal like this takes dedication, love, and of course, a Data Science-y approach.
Special thanks to Ally, Zia, and Bookbuddy for help in accomplishing this goal!
Also, special thanks to [@drob](https://twitter.com/drob) and [@juliasilge](https://twitter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2018 Joint Statistical Meeting Presentation</title>
      <link>/post/2018-joint-statistical-meeting-presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-joint-statistical-meeting-presentation/</guid>
      <description>I was honored to present some collaborative work between my friend Jim Pleuss and I at the 2018 Joint Statistical Meetings
The question we attemped to answer is: Do students who are grouped with others of like ability perform better?
Short answer: Not really.
Full details are included in my presentations repository on my Github here
The poster is located here
Went for a good run in Vancouv-R. #rstats #JSM2018 @MeetVancouver pic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2005 Ford F150 Gas Milage Analysis</title>
      <link>/post/ford-f150-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/ford-f150-analysis/</guid>
      <description>In February 2006, my dad and I split the cost of a 2005 Ford F150. He probably paid the larger half, but I believe he (and I) have got our money’s worth out of it as I still drive it to this day. Since the purchase, I have tracked the gas mileage every time I’ve filled up the tank. This tutorial uses this data set to highlight some functions in R to do the following:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2017 MORS Presentation</title>
      <link>/post/2017-mors-presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2017-mors-presentation/</guid>
      <description>Midway through my first semester teaching at West Point, my mentor, asked me what “scholarship” I was working on. To be honest, at the time, I was doing my best to make sure I understood what material I was teaching the next day and making sure my grading was up-to-date. I had been tinkering around with the idea of ‘data scraping’ which was a nebulous term to be then. I was intrigued by it and had google searched ways to get data in the days before (my old tried and true method of copy and paste was frustratingly slow…).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shiny Project: Experimentation with Leaflet, Shapefiles, and Interactivity</title>
      <link>/post/shiny-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/shiny-project/</guid>
      <description>Taking A Look Across The Country</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Helping A Colleague Explore Data</title>
      <link>/post/helping-a-colleague-explore-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/helping-a-colleague-explore-data/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionA colleague of mine asked me to help him explore a dataset in R. He has little experience in R, so I will provide as much detail as I can in this exploration. My goal here is to make this post both ‘learn-able’ and ‘replicable’.
Install and/or load necessary packagesif (!require(&amp;quot;tidyverse&amp;quot;)) install.packages(&amp;quot;tidyverse&amp;quot;)if (!require(&amp;quot;readr&amp;quot;)) install.packages(&amp;quot;readr&amp;quot;)if (!require(&amp;quot;lubridate&amp;quot;)) install.packages(&amp;quot;lubridate&amp;quot;)if (!require(&amp;quot;stringi&amp;quot;)) install.packages(&amp;quot;stringi&amp;quot;)Set Working Directory If Necessary# setwd(&amp;quot;//filepath/of/your/csvfile&amp;quot;)Read in dataWe use read_csv from the readr package because it does a better job than the base read.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog Introduction</title>
      <link>/post/blog-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/blog-introduction/</guid>
      <description>As my experience with statistics, computer science, and the all encompasing term, data science, increases, I have decided that it is time to share some of my projects.
Creating this blog serves several purposes.
It archives some projects I’ve created.It makes my work public so I can receive (hopefully) constructive feedback to improve my tools/analysis.
It helps me share what I’ve learned with the community that has been so helpful to me.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>