<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Beatnavy on Dusty Turner</title>
    <link>/categories/beatnavy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Beatnavy on Dusty Turner</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© This post is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License，please give source if you likes to quote or reproduce.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/beatnavy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing The turnR Package</title>
      <link>/post/introducing-the-turnr-package/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/introducing-the-turnr-package/</guid>
      <description>InspirationAt the 2019 New York R Conference, Emily Robinson gave a great talk called “Everything You Wanted to Know About Making R Packages but Were Afraid to Ask” (Note: This link will be live once the video is published). I dabbled with creating a package before, but her talk made creating a package so much more tangible (and scale-able), and it pushed me over the edge to try again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fantasy Football - Navigating the ESPN and Yahoo! APIs</title>
      <link>/post/espn-yahoo-api-navigation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/espn-yahoo-api-navigation/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionFor the last two years I’ve had the honor of being the commissioner for the West Point Department of Mathematical Science’s Fantasy Football League. This year we had 20 managers so we had to split our department into two leagues. I hosted one using ESPN and a colleague hosted on in Yahoo.
In order to compare our two leagues, I will use the ESPN API and YAHOO API to download our league’s information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mathlete Fantasy Football Analysis</title>
      <link>/post/mathlete-fantasy-football-analysis2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/mathlete-fantasy-football-analysis2018/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionIn my previous post, I worked through how to get your league information from the ESPN and YAHOO APIs.
The motivation for this project was to compare two leagues performances over the 2018 fantasy football season. As the ring leader of the West Point Department of Mathematical Sciences fantasy football league, we had 20 managers. This, of course, is too many for one league so we split the teams across two leagues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2018 NCAA College Bowl Pick &#39;em</title>
      <link>/post/2018-ncaa-college-bowl-pick-em/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-ncaa-college-bowl-pick-em/</guid>
      <description>Bowl Season!The new and improved version of my NCAA College Bowl Pick’em Shiny App is available below.
Incorporated this year are a few (transparent) things.
Bowl selections automatically lock once they start.
Bowl results automatically update once they are complete.
Multiple scoring techniques (weighted by confidence and raw).
Analysis of everyone’s picks.
Enjoy!
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vancouver: Joint Statistical Meeting Presentation</title>
      <link>/post/2018-joint-statistical-meeting-presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-joint-statistical-meeting-presentation/</guid>
      <description>I was honored to present some collaborative work between my friend Jim Pleuss and I at the 2018 Joint Statistical Meetings
The question we attemped to answer is: Do students who are grouped with others of like ability perform better?
Short answer: Not really.
Full details are included in my presentations repository on my Github here
The poster is located here
Oh, and Jim and I went for a little “R” run as well in Vancouver.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2005 Ford F150 Gas Milage Analysis</title>
      <link>/post/ford-f150-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/ford-f150-analysis/</guid>
      <description>In February 2006, my dad and I split the cost of a 2005 Ford F150. He probably paid the larger half, but I believe he (and I) have got our money’s worth out of it as I still drive it to this day. Since the purchase, I have tracked the gas mileage every time I’ve filled up the tank. This tutorial uses this data set to highlight some functions in R to do the following:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with Dates in R</title>
      <link>/post/dates-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/dates-in-r/</guid>
      <description>A Little About Dates in RBefore we launch into any analysis that contains dates, we should know a few important nuggets about how R handles date-like objects.
There are 3 date/time classes are built in to R
- Date
- POSIXct
- POSIXlt
Base RFirst, base R can read a string of text and convert it to a date class. To help it read the date, you must tell R what date format your character string should expect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tracking My Cadet&#39;s Summer Plans</title>
      <link>/post/tracking-my-cadets-summer-plans/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/tracking-my-cadets-summer-plans/</guid>
      <description>Tracking my cadet’s summer plans with dplyr and ggplot. The interactive ShinyApp is below!% --% --% --% --% --% --% --% --% --% --</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2018 NY R Conference Presentation</title>
      <link>/post/2018-ny-r-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-ny-r-conference/</guid>
      <description>Was honored to speak at this years 2018 New York R Conference hosted by Lander Analytics and Work-Bench. Jared Lander sure knows how to host a good party, I mean, conference.
My Slides are available, and you can contact me at dusty.s.turner@gmail.com
Here is the youtube link to the video:

Oh, and I got to go for a little run before the conferece!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Scraping Presentation: Center for Data Analysis and Statistics</title>
      <link>/post/data-scraping-presentation-center-for-data-analysis-and-statistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/data-scraping-presentation-center-for-data-analysis-and-statistics/</guid>
      <description>On 17 April 2018, I gave a tutorial to the Department of Mathematical Sciences at West Point and the Sports Analytics Club. The Power Point presentation, R file, and R Markdown file are at my github page at this link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2017 NCAA College Bowl Pick &#39;em</title>
      <link>/post/2017-ncaa-college-bowl-pick-em/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2017-ncaa-college-bowl-pick-em/</guid>
      <description>Bowl Season!Its one of the best times of the year. In order to celebrate (and to participate in a little competition), I put together a Shiny App to track my collegues picks over the season. Its improved throughout the season, and there are still improvment’s I’d like to add - but below is a working prototype.
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2017 MORS Presentation</title>
      <link>/post/2017-mors-presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2017-mors-presentation/</guid>
      <description>Midway through my first semester teaching at West Point, my mentor, asked me what “scholarship” I was working on. To be honest, at the time, I was doing my best to make sure I understood what material I was teaching the next day and making sure my grading was up-to-date. I had been tinkering around with the idea of ‘data scraping’ which was a nebulous term to be then. I was intrigued by it and had google searched ways to get data in the days before (my old tried and true method of copy and paste was frustratingly slow…).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shiny Project: Experimentation with Leaflet, Shapefiles, and Interactivity</title>
      <link>/post/shiny-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/shiny-project/</guid>
      <description>Taking A Look Across The Country</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Helping A Colleague Explore Data</title>
      <link>/post/helping-a-colleague-explore-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/helping-a-colleague-explore-data/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionA colleague of mine asked me to help him explore a dataset in R. He has little experience in R, so I will provide as much detail as I can in this exploration. My goal here is to make this post both ‘learn-able’ and ‘replicable’.
Install and/or load necessary packagesif (!require(&amp;quot;tidyverse&amp;quot;)) install.packages(&amp;quot;tidyverse&amp;quot;)if (!require(&amp;quot;readr&amp;quot;)) install.packages(&amp;quot;readr&amp;quot;)if (!require(&amp;quot;lubridate&amp;quot;)) install.packages(&amp;quot;lubridate&amp;quot;)if (!require(&amp;quot;stringi&amp;quot;)) install.packages(&amp;quot;stringi&amp;quot;)Set Working Directory If Necessary# setwd(&amp;quot;//filepath/of/your/csvfile&amp;quot;)Read in dataWe use read_csv from the readr package because it does a better job than the base read.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mathlete Fantasy Football Analysis</title>
      <link>/post/mathlete-fantasy-football-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/mathlete-fantasy-football-analysis/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionLets see who really has fantasy football bragging rights and who is just lucky (or unlucky).
During this analysis I will display most of my code. While this doesn’t provided the most pleasent visual experience, it will hopefully help the reader learn from my examples. (And potentially provide feedback on how to improve my methods.)
LibrariesThe libraries I will use for this analysis are the following:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog Introduction</title>
      <link>/post/blog-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/blog-introduction/</guid>
      <description>As my experience with statistics, computer science, and the all encompasing term, data science, increases, I have decided that it is time to share some of my projects.
Creating this blog serves several purposes.
It archives some projects I’ve created.It makes my work public so I can receive (hopefully) constructive feedback to improve my tools/analysis.
It helps me share what I’ve learned with the community that has been so helpful to me.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>